Axel Eldrian Hadiwibowo

Bandung, Indonesia | LinkedIn : axeleldrian | 089638959321 | eldrianaxel1@gmail.com

EMPLOYMENT OBJECTIVE

A motivated individual with in-depth knowledge of web development, machine learning, statistics, and analytical skills, known for the ability to quickly grasp new concepts. With over 2+ years of experience in software development, I am seeking a role where I can utilize my extensive knowledge, continue learning, and grow as a professional. Committed to working collaboratively within a team environment to deliver innovative solutions and contribute to the success of the organization.

EDUCATION

Universitas Pendidikan Indonesia

Bandung, Indonesia

Final year student Computer Science (GPA: 3.85/4.00)

August 2020 - present

- Organization: BEM KEMAKOM UPI, BEM FPMIPA UPI
- Awards: Win 3rd Place Innovation System Competition Healthkathon BPJS KESEHATAN RI 2022, Win 2nd Place Software Development Competition CODE 2022, Champion expectations 3 UI/UX Design Dimas-TI AMLI 2022

EXPERIENCE

PT.GITS Indonesia

Bandung, Indonesia

Software Development

February 2023 – June 2023

- Understanding and implementing the concept of Object and Key Result in performing tasks
- Implemented Scrum methodology with Trunk-Based Development approach, combining iterative and incremental development with continuous integration and collaboration principles in software development.
- As a Software Development, proficient in multiple programming tools such as Nuxt, Vue.js, TypeScript, and Jest for unit testing purposes.
- Successfully completed unit testing, achieving a high statement coverage of 67.8%, comprehensive branch coverage of 55.1%, satisfactory function coverage of 63.9%, and comprehensive line coverage of 67.5%.

OWL COURSE (Computer assisted test website)

Bandung, Indonesia

Project Manager & Full Stack Developer (freelance)

December 2022 – January 2023

- Trusted to work with owlcourse.id in creating a computer assisted test website to assist the selection process for POLRI, TNI, KEDINASAN &, CPNS in Makassar
- As a Back-end, Creating an API for owlcourse.id using CodeIgniter as framework and MySQL as a DBMS.
- As a Front-end, Creating a website using ReactJS and TailwindCSS as framework, and Figma as design tools.
- Design, create, present daily progress, testing, until deployment website to server with CPanel.

SIPETIS (Augmented reality-based autism detection website)

Bandung, Indonesia

Full Stack Developer (freelance)

September 2022 – December 2022

- Collaborate with professors, several lecturers, and seniors in the planning, creation, and development of augmented reality-based autism detection websites.
- Design, create and present web daily progress to the team.
- Create a website using Laravel and TailwindCSS as framework, and Figma as design tools and with MVC architectural.

HONOR & AWARD

3rd WINNER INNOVATION SYSTEM

Indonesia

- As a team leader, successfully organized the team to work together in this competition to create a website application and API with a blockchain-based system until the final round.
- Creating applications using: ReactJS, TailwindCSS, ExpressJS, Azure Confidential Ledger, NodeJS, MySQL.
- Successfully eliminated 415 teams from 417 teams registered in the innovation system category through 4 stages before entering the Grand Final in this national competition.
- Bringing the good name of UPI because the announcement of the winner is reported on many news platforms such as detik.com, Tribunnews.com, Jamkesnews.com, bisnis.tempo.co.

2nd WINNER SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Competition CODE 2022 AMIKOM

August 2022

- With the team created a website-based application and implemented a Blockchain system in it to support data security and transparency.
- Creating applications using: Laravel 9, Tailwind CSS, Azure Confidential Ledger, PHP.
- Be the only team from West Java who won and managed to get rid of more than 4 teams from different universities in Indonesia.

CHAMPION EXPECTATIONS 3 UI/UX DESIGN

Indonesia

Dimas-TI AMLI 2022

June 2022

- With the team, create a ui/ux design for a mobile application about prevention and efforts to deal with global warming.
- Create designs and prototypes using applications using Figma as a tool in this national competition.

ONLINE COURSES

MyEduSolve (PT Dwi Inti Putra)

Remote

Kampus Merdeka Studi Independent (Data Scientist)

August 2022 – December 2022

- Learn how to become a data scientist, from understanding statistics, understanding programming languages, and how to work with machine learning.
- Learned 5 topics needed by Data Scientist, such as Databases (SQL), Python Programming Language, Fundamentals of Statistics, Data Visualization using Power BI, and Machine Learning
- Worked on several mini projects, such as Customer Segmentation, Telco Customer Churn Prediction, and Machine Learning Model Deployment.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

BEM KEMAKOM UPI

Bandung, Indonesia

Head of Political Bureau

2022 - 2023

- Running a work program by discussing political issues that occur in collaboration with 2 other members.
- Succeeded in becoming the steering committee for several small to large work programs such as P2M KEMAKOM 2022, Donor Darah 2022, etc.

BEM KEMAKOM UPI

Bandung, Indonesia

Staff of Advocacy, Social and Political Division

2021 - 2022

- Became the head of the event by overseeing 30+ members and successfully held 9 programs that had been planned smoothly at P2M KEMAKOM 2021.
- Create new work programs and successfully lead 2 event about political issues and run the event in a new style.

LICENSE & CERTIFICATION

- Achievements (2022): IT Specialist Databases: Certiport A Person Vue Business
- Achievements (2022): IT Specialist Python: Certiport A Person Vue Business

OTHERS

Skills: Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Power BI, Azure) | DBMS (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server) | Framework (Laravel, Codeigniter, React JS, Hardhat, TailwindCSS) | Programming Language (HTML, CSS, Typescript, Javascript, C, Python, Solidity, PHP) | Git, Github, Gitlab | Testing Framework (Jest) | Software Development (Scrum agile)

Interests: Data Scientist, Data Analysis, Web Developer, Front-end Developer, Web3 Developer, Blockchain Developer.